Once upon a time, there was a man who died.
The man had the power to make stories come true,
so his hands were cut off by the people,
who were afraid of tragedies becoming reality.
When the man died, the people heaved a great sigh of relief.
As it turned out, however, when his hands were cut off,
the man had been writing a story in his own blood.
That was a story he could continue spinning even after he died.
A story of the man himself.
Oh!
What?
This can't be!
To think the words of true love, Tutu was supposed to say.
Princess Crayhe ended up saying it stiff,
even though she was raised on Raven's blood
and shouldn't even know how to love.
Regardless, you still will be unable to escape tragedy,
my dear little duck.
Princess Crayhe
Are you glad to have it, Prince?
I don't know.
Seiya, I have another question.
Do you think you'll love me?
I don't know.
Well, just tell me you love me.
I love you.
I want to hear you say that you love me.
Trust me, Muto, you do love me.
Please, I love you!
My Prince!
I have ever since I was little.
I've always loved you!
Rue.
He took Rue.
You monster!
Relax.
I haven't killed her yet.
She's deep in my stomach.
I should have done this in that fight long ago
and saved us all the trouble.
She's just a human girl.
I kidnapped on a whim and raised, but she's been quite useful.
If you kill me, you'll be killing the girl within me as well.
Likewise, if you steal me away, you have no choice but to offer up your heart to me.
I can't fight even if I return the last heart shard. How horrible!
Prince, I demand you give me your heart at once.
It's hilarious.
Ha, ha, ha, ha, ha, ha, ha, ha, ha, ha, ha, ha, ha.
Ha ha ha ha.
Still resisting?
You mean to imply you still have some chance of success, Prince?
Princess Tutu.
Yes?
I would like for you to return my final heart shard.
What?
Please give it to me.
I have to save her.
No, I...
I want to...
save Rue.
Excruciating pain of having Raven's blood eat at your heart.
I know that pain.
It starts in the weak places in your heart and spreads ruthlessly.
You can't even stop yourself from hurting the people who are important to you.
Rue has stood up under the burden of that suffering all alone ever since she was small.
Her love was frail, and she was always afraid of losing love.
The more she loved, the more she suffered.
But there was no one she could even seek help from.
But she never thought to stop loving.
With words of true love, she led me out of the Raven's darkness.
It's my turn to protect her now.
And if possible, I'd like to take Rue as my princess.
So, Princess Tutu, please give me the last heart shard.
Yes.
If your heart is not complete, I cannot gain eternal life from it.
I almost rushed things in my eagerness.
What?
What's the matter?
The pendant won't come off.
What's going on?
Why won't it?
Princess Tutu, I grant you until dawn.
You must give the final shard back to the prince by then.
If you fail to do this, I will tear the prince's heart into pieces.
This tea is the blend that Drosselmeyer liked to drink while he was working.
He used three parts Darjeeling and then added a psalm...
Tell me again why I must do this?
It certainly is noisy.
What's going on?
What?
Bathed in this noble blood, all people will become crows.
Now celebrate my triumphant return.
P.K. and Lillie?
Mr. Cat?
You'd better hurry.
You haven't much time to do.
I can't take it off.
Why not?
I wonder.
This is bad for...
Altor, I'm begging you, would you please be a little quiet...
Well, well.
That person writing at that desk looks a lot like me when I was younger.
Could it be?
No, I'm mistaken.
I would never waver about writing.
Ha ha ha ha ha ha.
So you're Drosselmeyer.
Hmm, these things all look a lot like what I use, but most of them appear to be fakes.
You're trying to be responsible about your writing, aren't you?
Well, that's why you can't write.
You have to understand that when you're writing stories, you should do it more freely and irresponsibly.
Just follow your own feelings.
I have no desire to become like you, a demented, sadistic fossil who toys with people's fates for a lark.
That thinking won't get us anywhere.
Mewtwo!
The Raven has revived and all of the Prince's heart has returned to him except for the shard in Princess Tutu's pendant.
What?
My hand's writing by itself.
You see, you have my blood running through your veins.
That was the lake called Despair.
It was dark and deep just like Duck's eyes.
What are you intending to make me write?
The sorrowful yet beautiful story of Little Duck.
The story of Duck?
At that moment, Duck could hear a voice.
It was the voice of Drosselmeyer, the man who controlled the story.
Duck!
It's because you're scared to let go of being Princess Tutu that you can't give back the heart shard, right?
No, that's not it.
You're afraid to part with the Prince.
I just want...
Rue would be carved into the Prince's heart for eternity because she gave herself over to the Raven.
And by keeping the heart shard, Duck would live on in the Prince's heart as Princess Tutu and not as an ugly little Duck.
Is it... is it all my fault?
Yes, it is.
And in order to take off the pendant, you'll have to lay down your life.
Duck began to sink into the lake of despair, walking further and further in...
Stop it!
Don't go, Duck!
Deeper and deeper...
Stop it!
What?
Duck!
Kier!
There are crows all over town!
Duck?
Where did you go, Sora?
Duck!
Duck?
Tuck?
State...
?!
Quidditch!
I've got to find...
Don't go out there, it's dangerous!
What?
Never mind that!
What happened to your hand?
And when did you write a story?
What happened?
Tell me!
Drosselmeyer came, and he Drosselmeyer?
Bastard made me write the story.
You mean, Drosselmeyer was here in this room?
Yes.
Magnificent!
What's wrong?
Nothing.
Hey, where are you going?
Hey, wait!
What's going on?
It looks exactly like the Crow Festival scene
that took place in The Prince and the Raven.
So the Raven has cursed them.
Damn it!
Hey!
The Raven's curse, is it?
I wonder if she's alright then?
The Lake of Despair, where is that?
There you are, Zura!
Uzura!
That just disappeared, Zura!
So you were with her when it happened?
Where is she?
This way, Zura!
I'm sorry.
I'm sorry, Rue.
I'm sorry, Muto.
If I vanish,
the Heart Shard
will return to you.
This way, Zura!
What?
Outside the gate?
I've never even thought of leaving this city.
Now I see.
I was being controlled by Drosselmeyer's story.
That's why.
It looks like the story started to spread beyond the city walls.
What are you waiting for, Zura?
Oh, sorry!
Hurry up, Zura!
Here, Zura!
Oh, sorry!
Hurry up, Zura!
Here, Zura!
Doc!
What's with this lake?
For some reason, I can breathe.
Is this just another stage setting Drosselmeyer prepared?
I thought I was doing my best for Muto's sake.
But was it for my own sake?
Just like Mr. Drosselmeyer said,
I'm really thinking that I don't want to return Muto to the story.
I'm really sorry.
Doc!
Vakir?
Vakir!
Doc!
Vakir, the pendant won't come off.
It's the last of Muto's heart shards.
And Muto asked me to give it back to him, but...
Muto said he wants to make Rue his princess.
And I know he wants to save her from the raven.
But it just won't come off.
All this is my fault.
Because I'm thinking that deep inside my heart,
I don't want the story to ever end.
Vakir and Lillie and Mr. Cat and the others turned into crows.
But even after that...
Idiot.
You're not the only one.
What?
You're not the only one, Doc.
I don't want to...
No, the fact of the matter is that nobody wants to see the story come to an end.
Nobody save Muto himself.
I still can't write a story about Muto either.
Stop blaming just yourself.
Everyone is scared of being restored to their true selves.
They're used to being given rules and stories that shelter them from the business of living.
The real you is a duck.
And the real me...
In the end, the real me has been protected since my childhood.
I can't protect anyone.
But even if that is what I am truly like, I want to end the story once and for all.
I want to protect Muto and you because of my own feelings, not some role given to me.
Even if I use up all of my power.
When that happens, I'll go back to being just a bird.
And I won't ever study ballet with everybody again.
That's fine, isn't it?
After all, that's who you really are.
Yeah.
And even after that time comes, I will stay by your side forever.
Fuck you.
It's strange. Until a short while ago, I thought it was okay for me to simply vanish.
But now, I'm weak.
But for some reason, Fakir always makes me stronger.
Somehow.
Let's go back to being our true selves now.
Yes.
Let's compose an end for this story.
Not just for Muto's sake, but for our own sakes as well.
Yes.
It came off.
Hey, the pendant came off just now, Fakir.
Let's return it to Muto.
Despair runs much deeper than that.
What?
It's Ruu!
Ruu, I'm coming to get you!
Hold on.
Huh?
Let's go back.
What about Ruu?
Muto will be able to save Ruu.
Our job is to save Muto. We have to hurry.
Great.
That's Uzura. She'll guide us out of here.
Oh, are you okay, Sora?
Thank you so much, Uzura.
Yes, thank you.
You took your pendant off, Sora.
Uh-huh.
We've got to give it back to Muto fast.
Fakir, will you write a story about me just one more time?
That way we'll combine our we-want-to-protect-Muto powers.
Combine our powers, huh?
Is it really okay for me to write a story about you?
Yeah.
Okay then, I'll be back.
Right.
Well, goodbye, Uzura.
All right.
Huh?
Uzura.
Princess Tutu, huh?
Huh?
Hey, Doc!
Do your best, Sora!
Princess Tutu ran, determined to return the last Heart Shard to the Prince.
She didn't do it just for the Prince, but for all the people.
When she thought of it that way, there was no more hesitation.
The morning bell had not yet rung.
The Prince was quietly waiting for Tutu to come.
Prince, I'm sorry to have made you wait.
I never doubted you would come for me.
The feelings you returned to me.
The feelings of love, affection, sorrow, loneliness.
All of my feelings told me that Tutu was sure to come for me.
The feelings you returned to me.
The feelings of love, affection, sorrow, loneliness.
All of my feelings told me that Tutu was sure to come for me.
Tutu quietly gazed into the Prince's eyes, then took off the pendant.
The final Heart Shard was shaped like a pair of fluttering wings.
Wings for the people who had spent a comfortable time inside the story, to leave the nest with.
Wings for the Prince to return to himself with.
Goodbye now, Mewto.
Goodbye.
Shushu!
What?
You were...
Something so small and fragile accomplished this.
Thank you, Princess Tutu.
Quack.
This... is the true Prince.
Ha-ha-ha-ha-ha-ha-ha-ha-ha-ha-ha.
So you've finally been restored, Prince.
It's the beginning of a tragedy.
The Prince can't fight for his princess's capture inside the enemy.
Tutu has become a mere duck.
The night has long been useless and the princess will waste away in the depths of despair.
What will you do now, Prince?
Will you shatter your heart a second time?
Ha-ha-ha-ha-ha-ha-ha-ha-ha-ha-ha?
Tutu has become a mere duck.
The night has long been useless,
and the princess will waste away in the depths of despair.
What will you do now, Prince?
Will you shatter your heart a second time?
The real me is just a duck, but I can still dance.
No one to trick me, no one for me to resent.
There's nothing here, not even loving.
Everything that happened in Gold-Crowned Town,
this thing was recording as a story.
In my name as Prince Siegfried,
I call the name of the Princess.
Let's give this story a happy ending.
All you children who love stories, come gather round.
Let's listen ,
everyone is used to be永 Nachman.
The story is a key step in the imagination.
the story is an bouncy curl which is enough.
When we find certain trees, we can stand up.
Even the trees...
No , the trees...